Go on.
Focus on expanding your senses.
You can break a spell by severing
its linchpin, even with a regular sword.
I feel like I've gotten the hang of it.
Your Majesty! Your Majesty!
You've a letter from Princess Nephelli!
Directly from Nephelli?
~ Unseen Visage ~
It seems the prime minister of Yarda
is trying to oust the crown prince, Savas.
Which is why Princess Nephelli wants
to stay in Farsas for the time being.
Well, turning her away would come off
as unnatural, so I've replied with a "yes."
Of course.
Your Majesty's on good terms
with Princess Nephelli.
Will it be okay with Tinasha here?
We can't have her making enemies with Yarda.
I believe that's in your hands...
I'll warn her the next time I see her.
Though she seems busy
breaking my curse lately.
Your Majesty, please act
with the utmost prudence.
I'll mention it during our training.
If I talk to her outdoors,
she can't break any windows.
That's not what I meant.
There's less than a month until her coronation.
She'll handle it just fine.
That's just how the two of us are built.
That singing...
It's Tinasha.
I hear someone in the palace got married,
and they're holding a wedding banquet.
She sure is talented.
I'll make an appearance later.
Congratulations on getting married.
Huh? Oscar?
You know this is alcoholic.
What? But it's sweet.
It's sweet and alcoholic.
Huh?
When I get drunk, my magic
goes a little out of control.
That's no good.
I swear...
Put on sealing ornaments.
This is a festive occasion.
Sure.
Hold on, lemme try again.
It's a cat.
Yeah, I can tell!
Stop using magic!
Your Majesty!
We've received a reply from Yarda.
The princess should arrive in two days.
Got it.
Please make the necessary arrangements.
C-Certainly.
Oscar, are you gonna get married?
Not sure. Why do you ask?
If you've got something to say, out with it.
No, I'm just here to be of use to you.
Marry whoever you like.
Sure thing.
I'll find a queen who doesn't
break the palace windows.
I hate you!
And I hate mages who can't hold their liquor.
You big fat dummy!
I liked your singing, though.
I apologize for my sudden intrusion.
I'm sure staying in an unfamiliar land
isn't easy, but please enjoy your stay.
Thank you so much for your generosity.
I believe the princess of Tuldarr
is here as well.
Yes, I'll have her say hello.
Prince Legis introduced me to her before.
I must say, she's beautiful.
She's like a powder keg.
An intense personality,
and I don't care much for her looks.
It's been a long time, Princess Nephelli.
I'm honored to see you again.
I could say the same thing.
I hear it's not too long
until you ascend the throne.
Things have been hectic for me,
so please forgive my lack of courtesy.
You should defend with your magic.
No, that wouldn't be fair.
Good afternoon.
Out on a stroll?
I was hoping to get some light exercise.
Princess Tinasha,
do you two always spar like this?
Yes, I'm having him train me.
Disperse.
Where's it coming from?
I'll find out.
Mila.
Yes, ma'am!
Go after the assassin.
Keep him alive, if possible.
If not, feel free to kill him.
Right away.
U-Um, what's going on?
Looks like an assassin made it
through the palace barrier.
I think they escaped,
but it'd be best to go back inside.
It's safe to say their target
was Princess Nephelli.
However, this man is just a hired hand.
Having just a hired hand break
through the barrier is still a problem.
The barrier prevents
unauthorized teleportation from outside,
but you can still enter on foot.
So he had someone's help
from within the palace?
Als, make him talk.
As you wish.
Get up!
What a hassle.
Even if the Yarda prime minister
is implicated here,
that's an issue for their nation.
The most I can do is
let them know what happened.
You could get involved
if you were engaged to their princess.
Get engaged just for that?
That's a big leap of logic.
An engagement would give you just cause
to meddle in their affairs to an extent.
Don't you think that's the reason
she came here to begin with?
Thus the assassin, huh?
If Nephelli dies, there'd be no risk
of me poking my nose into Yarda.
Having the princess die in Farsas
would let them blame you as well.
Oscar sure is friendly
with the princess of Yarda.
If she bothers you that much,
why not just kill her?
I'm not doing that!
Travis.
Aw, man.
Just murder her.
Giving into temptation is easier.
You again?
What do you want this time?
I'm bored, so I came to laugh at you.
The prince of Yarda is a timid one.
Unlike the prime minister,
who's quite remarkable.
Is that right?
He's willing to make small
sacrifices for the big picture,
and he does whatever it takes
for a quick resolution.
And how do you know that?
Because I'm currently in Gandona.
I'm aware that Gandona
borders both Farsas and Yarda,
but does that have anything to do with you?
Sure it does.
I'm acting as the guardian
to the heir to Gandona's throne.
What?
Well? Feel like killing that princess yet?
Don't you think you should
make better use of your powers?
People are defined by more than their power.
What's wrong with using what you've got?
That man is what you're after, isn't it?
You can't win people over by killing others.
So be it, then.
That aside, an insect has made
its way into this castle, you know.
You mean the assassin?
I feel sorry for the princess, having
someone after her even in a foreign nation.
Not that.
A different insect.
Eh?
Enjoy your fruitless efforts.
You'll be left in the lurch if you place
too much confidence in your abilities.
What do you mean, "left in the lurch?"
Seriously, what's his deal?
The king of Farsas hinted at the fact
that there may be a spy hiding in our midst.
Her Highness had assumed
we were all trustworthy,
and now she's practically
confined herself to her room.
Is something wrong?
Oh, Valt.
I can't believe an assassin is after her
all the way here in Farsas.
I was thinking we might have
been better off in Yarda.
We stand a better chance here in Farsas.
And I'm sure the king of Farsas will prove
to be a strong ally for Her Highness.
We might even see a partnership
between our countries in the future.
Well, I'm sure Her Highness would be happy—
Your Highness!
She met her end while
tasting the soup for poison.
It's a commonplace potion.
A number of others ate the soup
in question, but they were all fine.
No potions were detected in the soup pot.
The meal was brought by a lady-in-waiting
and an officer from Yarda.
That officer has now gone missing.
The lady-in-waiting claims that
he handed her the food.
He's so suspicious, it's almost funny.
That officer's name is Eneas,
and he was close with both ladies-in-waiting.
That is how I believe
he was able to pull this off.
I understand it's a lot to ask,
but could you please assist
Princess Nephelli in this time?
I will be more vigilant, of course,
and I intend to find the culprit.
Thank you very much,
but that's not what I meant.
Princess Nephelli has had an interest
in you since ten years ago.
If it's possible—
I understand.
I'll do what I can.
Feel like poking your nose in?
I'm left with no choice.
In that case, I'll help.
Are you sure?
Don't you have to prepare for your coronation?
I have Legis lending me his support.
Sorry about this.
I want to settle this matter before you leave.
Incidentally, breaking your curse
should take about two more weeks.
I see.
And you won't mess up?
Don't be mean like that!
You're...
My name is Valt, Your Highness.
You're suppressing your magic.
In truth, your magic exceeds that
of a nation's chief mage.
I wouldn't go that far.
That said, most of my magic is acquired,
so I'd rather not have others know about it.
So have you come to me because
you have clues to the assassin's identity?
No, that's not it.
I was hoping you could answer a question
I had about spell compositions.
Eh?
I can't thank you enough.
Oh, no, it served as a good
change of pace for me.
Now I can return to guarding
Princess Nephelli with no reservations.
The king of Farsas said he'll cooperate,
so the engagement should be any day now.
Eh?
Yarda is acting like they're engaged already.
Those two have always been close,
so I'm sure they'll make a happy couple.
So now you can finally be free, too.
Please take care,
Queen of Tuldarr.
Free...
Who that man marries is none of my business.
Are you feeling all right, Princess Nephelli?
Thank you for your concern.
I apologize that I must return
to Tuldarr in the middle of our search.
Are you leaving right now?
No, I still have some time.
Then why not regale us
with a song before leaving?
A song?
Manifold colors bathed in light
Drifting unknown to all
The shadows of time
Carried away in the wind
Twilight recedes away
As remnants of a dream diverge
With that, I'll be taking my leave.
Nephelli.
Yes?
Tomorrow...
Why don't we go out for some fresh air?
You wouldn't want to get sunburned.
Th-Thank you!
I don't think you'd get lost,
but stay close to me.
We'll reach a lake at the end of this forest.
Your Highness!
Gait!
Are you all right?
Lucanos! Valt!
Watch our surroundings!
Your Highness, let's return
to the palace for now.
I'll open a teleportation portal.
But...
Your safety is our top priority.
So you're the one?
It can't be!
Your Highness!
Wh-Where's Her Highness?
She's with Oscar.
You confused the two of us because
of my curse song from last night.
Although it didn't seem to work on one of you.
It's too late to back down.
Did you kill the officer who went missing?
Damn you!
Time to tell us whose orders
you've been acting on.
Go on, before you die.
Oscar!
Why won't you use your magic?!
Are you an idiot?!
I made it in time thanks to your teleport.
Thanks.
Think nothing of it.
I can't have her dying here.
So why's he still moving?
He must have swallowed
a seed with a forbidden curse.
It activates when one receives a mortal wound,
bestowing upon them power
that exceeds physical limits.
I see.
And you end up with that.
Oscar.
Can you see the magic stagnating within him?
Kind of.
I see faint white lines like the veins
of a leaf across his entire body.
The linchpin is the part where
his magic is visibly concentrated.
I see where it is, but a stab there
would normally kill someone.
Do that, and I'll keep him alive
so he can at least be interrogated.
Don't get any more injuries.
Now you belong to me.
Now you can finally return
to your home country.
You've gone through so much here.
N-No...
King Oscar...
Do you remember my
proposal from ten years ago?
From the ceasefire agreement?
I do.
If I asked you to marry me now,
like I did ten years ago, would you say yes?
Let me see.
Should it turn out to benefit both of us,
I'll be the one to submit an offer.
Yes.
Thank you very much for all of your help.
Are you sure it's okay
to let Princess Nephelli leave?
There's no reason for her to stay any longer.
I'm sure she's keen to leave as well.
But I thought you two...
In that case, can I stay here a little longer?
Whatever suits you best.
Until you become queen, that is.
What's wrong?
I'm here to follow up on the Yarda matter.
There was something that caught my eye.
Wasn't there a second mage, other than Gait?
You mean Valt?
The thing is, we found no records
of him in Yarda's royal court.
What?
Gait and the princess said that he'd
joined the court five years ago,
but it seems that was a false memory
that had been temporarily planted.
So where's Valt now?
We've already lost track of him.
Actually, his appearance closely matches
the mage from Delilah's testimony.
The mage who had ties to that cult?!
If the two are one and the same...
That would mean Valt was the one
who poisoned Tinasha.
So why did he help us this time around?
Yes... why?
Investigate this further.
Whatever agenda he may have,
don't let him get away with anything else.
Don't worry about it.
You just focus on what you need to do.
So now you can finally be free, too.
I'll be fine.
I came here to be of use to you.
~ Returning the Promise ~